<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Koga</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 10:51:26 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 10:51:26 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating &amp; Hosting a Blog on Github Pages</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post shows how I created and hosted my blog on Github Pages. While it details my experiences, it can be used as a starting guide for anyone looking to do so. I wrote this to show that it isn’t difficult to get one running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I went and bought a domain at &lt;a href=&quot;https://namecheap.com&quot;&gt;Namecheap&lt;/a&gt; since strange TLDs (like .tech) have a deal that makes them only $0.88. It took about 30 to 40 minutes for the DNS registars to be updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use Github Pages (GP) - a free service offered by Github that lets me host a personal static website through a repository - to host this website as everything is stored on Gitub’s servers without any help from me. I made a &lt;em&gt;CNAME&lt;/em&gt; file in this website’s repository and put just my domain in it like the GP docs say to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website itself is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; one. Their website states that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jekyll is a simple, blog-aware, static site generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that it can be used to host a blog with greater ease than a traditional static HTML. It is also supported by Github Pages which was the deal breaker for me. You can find out more about Jekyll and how to use it &lt;a href=&quot;https://scotch.io/tutorials/getting-started-with-jekyll-plus-a-free-bootstrap-3-starter-theme&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, making and hosting a blog on Github Pages isn’t a dificult thing to do as my post - hopefully - illustrates. Feel free to contact me for help at &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#116;&amp;#104;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#107;&amp;#111;&amp;#103;&amp;#097;&amp;#064;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#116;&amp;#104;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#107;&amp;#111;&amp;#103;&amp;#097;&amp;#064;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>/up-and-running/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/up-and-running/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
